7 chapter eight of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 8 Ginger's Story
Continued The next time that Ginger and I were together at the paddock she told
me about her first place.
“After my breaking in,” she said, “I was bought by a dealer to match another
chestnut horse. For some weeks he drove us together, and then we were sold to a
fashionable gentleman, and were sent up to London. I had been driven with a check
Rain by the dealer, and I hated it worse than anything else; but in this place we
were rained far tighter, the coachman and his master thinking we looked more
stylish so. We were often driven about in the park and other fashionable places.
You who have never had a check rain on
don't know what it is, but I can tell you
it is dreadful. “I like to toss my head about and hold it as high as any horse;
but fancy now yourself, if you tossed your head up high and were obliged to
hold it there, and that for hours together, not able to move it at all,
except with a jerk still higher, your neck aching till you did not know how to
bear it. Besides that, to have two bits instead of one— —and mine was a sharp one,
it hurt my tongue and my jaw, and the blood from my tongue T colored the froth
that kept flying from my lips as I chafed and fritted at the bits and
rain It was worst when we had to stand by the hour waiting for our mistress at
some grand party or entertainment, and if I Fred or stamped with impatience the
whip was laid on. It was enough to drive one mad.” “Did not your master take any thought
for you?” I said. “No,” said she, “he only cared to have a stylish turnout, as they call
it; I think he knew very little about horses; he left that to his coachman, who
told him I had an irritable temper! that I had not been well broken to the check
reain but I should soon get used to it;
but he was not the man to do it, for when
I was in the stable, miserable and angry, instead of being smoothed and quieted by
kindness, I got only a sirly word or a blow. If he had been civil I would have
tried to bear it. I was willing to work, and ready to work hard too; but to be
tormented for nothing but their fancies angered me me. What right had they to
make me suffer like that? Besides the soreness in my mouth, and the pain in my
neck, it always made my windpipe feel bad, and if I had stopped there long I know
it would have spoiled my breathing; but I grew more and more restless and
irritable, I could not help it; and I began to snap and kick when anyone came
to harness me; for this the groom beat me, and one day, as they had just buckled us
into the carriage, and were straining my head up with that rain I began to plunge
and kick with all my might. I soon broke a lot of harness, and kicked myself clear;
so that was an end of that place. “After this I was sent to ttis
souls to be sold; of course I could not be warranted free from vice, so nothing
was said about that. My handsome appearance and good paces soon brought a
gentleman to bid for me, and I was bought by another dealer; he tried me in all
kinds of ways and with different bits, and he soon found out what I could not
bear. At last he drove me quite without a check rain and then sold me as a
perfectly quiet horse to a gentleman in the country; he was a good master, and I
was getting on very well, but his old groom left him and a new one came. This
man was as hard tempered and hard-handed as Samson; he always spoke in a rough,
impatient voice, and if I did not move in the stall the moment he wanted me, he
would hit me above the Hawks with his stable broom or the fork, whichever he
might have in his hand. Everything he did was rough, and I began to hate him; he
wanted to make me afraid of him, but I was too high metled for that, and one day
when he had aggravated me more than usual I bit him, which of course put him
in a great rage, and he began to hit me about the head with a riding
whip. After that he never dared to come into my stall again; either my heels or
my teeth were ready for him, and he knew it. I was quite quiet with my master, but
of course he listened to what the man said, and so I was sold again. “The same
dealer heard of me, and said he thought he knew one place where I should do well
it was a pity,' he said, 'that such a fine
horse should go to the bad, for want of a
real good chance,' and the end of it was that I came here not long before you did;
but I had then made up my mind that men were my natural enemies and that I must
defend myself. Of course it is very different here, but who knows how long it will
last? I wish I could think about things as you do; but I can't, after all I have
gone through.” “Well,” I said, “I think it would be a real
shame if you were to bite or kick JN or James.” “I don't mean to,” she said, “while
they are good to me. I did bite James once pretty sharp, but Jon said, 'Try her
with kindness,' and instead of punishing me as I expected, James came to me with
his arm bound up, and brought me a brand mash and stroked me; and I have never
snapped at him since, and I won't either.” I was sorry for Ginger, but of course I
knew very little then, and I thought most likely she made the worst of it; however,
I found that as the weeks went on she grew more gentle and cheerful, and had
lost the watchful, defiant look that she used to turn on any strange person who
came near her; and one day James said, “I do believe that may is getting quite
fond of me, she quite wined after me this morning when I had been rubbing her
forehead a i Jim it is the Berwick balls',” said John, “she'll be as good as Black
Beauty by and by; kindness is all the physic she wants, poor
thing!” Master noticed the change, too, and one day when he got out of the carriage
and came to speak to us, as he often did, he stroked her beautiful neck. “Well, my
pretty one, well, how do things go with you now? You are a good bit happier than
when you came to us, I think.” She put her nose up to him in a friendly, trustful
way, while he rubbed it gently. “We shall make a cure of her, John,”
he said. “Yes, sir, she's wonderfully improved; she's not the same creature
that she was; it's 'the Berwick balls', sir,” said John, laughing. This was a little joke of
John's; he used to say that a regular course of “the Berwick horse balls would
cure almost any vicious horse; these balls, he said, were made up of patience
and gentleness, firmness and petting, one pound of each to be mixed up with half a
pint of common sense, and given to the horse every day
end of chapter